The most overpowered way of doing this,
by the way, is just writing some very
quick and easy code to just have the
iframe follow your cursor. Right?
Whenever your cursor is not centered on
the invisible iframe, then just move it
so that it is
best part of when you can just, you
know, critical thing.
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
All right, sub hackers. Today we are
going to cover one of my favorite topics
in hacking that is iframes. This is
going to be just a little quick and
dirty episode on how I approach iframes,
how I use them in my sort of
methodology, things you need to know
about all the attributes that are on
there, um, and some common vulnerability
types and uncommon vulnerability types.
We we've got a couple on here, um, that
I think will will be really helpful.
Okay, so let's jump into it. Uh,
iframes, of course, are the ability uh,
in HTML, it's an iframe tag, um, or a a
HTML tag that allows you to embed
another page inside of your website.
Okay. So, why is that helpful? Well,
there's a lot of reasons why that's
helpful. First ones that comes to mind
is of course clickjacking. Now, you
know, now when I say clickjacking, I'm
sure a lot of you guys are triggered and
like, "Oh, this guy's a scrub. He's
talking about clickjacking." Guys, I
just want to like take a second to say
clickjacking can be an incredibly
impactful vulnerability, right? You
think about oneclick XSS, we we report
that all the time. You know this
clickjing can have very very similar
impact. Consider this scenario. You are
able to embed an authorization an oath
offflow into your into your own website
right with one click on your website you
know in this invisible iframe you are
able to get the victim to approve full
access to their account. That's full
account takeover in one click right. So
clickjacking gets a bad a bad rap. I
have submitted plenty of impactful
clickjacking reports that have gotten
bounties. Um, the reason it gets a bad
rap is people will report it without
pocking it at all. Right? So, they'll
just be like, "Exrame options headers
missing, critical clickjacking." That's
not the case, right? You need to find a
single point of failure click that can
make your clickjacking report uh uh
impactful for it to actually be a good
report. Okay? So, I know I said
clickjacking. Chill the heck out
everybody. Um, but I really do think
they can be very impactful. Okay? So
clickjecking is one of the things that
you can do uh to to have with iframes
that's impactful to hacking. The other
one is frame references. Okay. Um so
frame references are extremely important
when it comes to exploiting uh lots of
client side types of vulnerabilities.
The reason for that is that um if you
have a reference to a frame, you can
send a post message to it. If you're
same origin, you can uh sort of jump
into that page and grab the DOM and
manipulate it and that sort of thing. So
um especially in this era of uh like
same site lacks default cookies um
having a frame reference to a tople page
or something like that really allows you
to u manipulate that page a lot. Um but
the most common you know use for having
a frame reference is to send a post
message. Okay, what is a post message? A
post message is intert communication or
interframe communication for the
browser. Um and I really think that this
is still after me talking about it for
years and years and years, a underserved
uh attack service, right? Like a lot of
people just don't even look at post
messages at all. Um, and they're just
completely missing an API that lives in
the browser that is extremely important
to the browser security. Okay, so
definitely something to look into. I'll
talk more about post messages maybe on a
different like deep dive technical deep
dive episode like this. Um, but for now
what you need to know is that iframe is
one of the the
the okay there's like a decent amount of
ways to get a frame reference, but one
of the few ways to get a frame reference
is is is via iframe. Okay, so keep that
in mind. All right. Um, and then uh the
other two things that I have in this
like why they're useful section for the
iframe is windowame hijacking which is a
uh vulnerability that uh I'll talk to
you about a little bit later. And then
the second one is or the last one is
your uh hiding your attacks that take
time. So there sometimes there's like
either a post message based attack or um
some client side based flow that will
take a lot of time to exploit um and you
kind of need to have your attack be
hidden on your website um and you need
to be able to target the victim website.
Now unfortunately this doesn't happen
quite as much nowadays because of same
site lacks default cookies. you can't
really embed stuff quite as simply, but
um in certain scenarios, you can embed
this, you know, target page in in an
iframe on your site, distract the user
with like a game of click this, click
that, um and then, you know, have full
enough time to fully exploit your
vulnerability. So, um that is is what I
would say are some of the four top
reasons why iframes are are useful to um
to hackers. So let's go into uh some of
the attributes of iframes so we can
understand uh how they can be
manipulated, how they can be
used. Okay, the first one is um source
and source doc. Obviously these are
going to be the most impactful ones.
These are the ones that um control where
the iframe is pointed at. Okay, so
source uh simply allows you to point the
source of the iframe uh at a URL. Could
be a JavaScript URL. That's one of the
common ways to get XSS is an iframe
source JavaScript URL. Um could be a uh
you know absolute URL where you're
pointing to uh a different website and
embedding a victim page. Um rarely do we
see something like where it's a relative
URL. That's just like not super helpful
for attackers typically. Um and then
what is source do and why do I lump them
together? Well, source doc is sort of
the alternative to source and it is a um
attribute that allows you to define what
should be inside of the iframe directly
in the source doc attribute. Um, and
this is extremely helpful for several
things, but the first one that pops to
mind when I think about the source doc
attribute is the fact that you can write
a new DOM inside of that iframe. And
that is really really helpful when you
need to use a script tag in a uh postdom
rendering environment because uh a lot
of you guys know that if you try to do
an inner HTML sync in DOMXS and you try
to put a script tag in there, it will
not fire because the DOM has already
rendered and that's when script tags uh
trigger. So you can have an inner HTML
sync, put a script tag in there, it's
not going to do anything. However, um
and typically you can get around that by
using something like a um onevent
handler like an SVG onload or an image
on error um uh handler. Uh however,
sometimes you are limited or maybe you
need to in import a different origin,
right? Something like that or import
your script from a different origin. Um
and you want to use a script tag. Well,
uh you're kind of stuck until iframe
source stock comes in. So what you can
actually do is iframe source dock and
then inside of that source dock you can
define the script tag and since that
iframe is in a new DOM inside of the
iframe that script tag will trigger
resulting in XSS. Okay, so it's a little
bit of a roundabout way but you can
still accomplish the same goal and it
has saved my ass a couple times because
sometimes there's just a really weird
filter on there that doesn't allow for
um you know any sort of onevent handlers
or maybe there's a character limitation
or something like that. Um this one does
work. So ve very helpful. Um the other
thing is that source doc will be uh same
origin as the parent uh uh when it's
defined. So that is helpful for um just
being able to embed content inside the
page in an isolated DOM that is still
the same origin as the parent. Uh okay.
So that's source and source doc. I'm not
sure that there's a lot of other things
there that come to mind as far as like
tricks that a hacker needs to know. So
let's move on to the next one. The next
is the CSP attribute. Okay, now you guys
have all heard of CSP, content security
policy. It is the way that uh modern
browsers add additional um limitations
to what uh scripts can scripts can be
run uh styles can be run uh what what uh
hosts we can connect to, that sort of
thing. Let me get some water for a sec.
Lovely. Okay. Um, so CSP is is often
used and in this scenario, um, as an
attacker, oftentimes if if you're coming
up against the CSP attribute, then
you're trying to get out of that CSP or
get around that CSP. Now, we could spend
a whole episode on how we block uh, how
do we get around CSP's blocks, right?
Um, and probably we will at some point.
Uh but for what for what you need to
know right now, there's a CSP attribute
that can be applied uh directly to the
iframe. And this has a couple of cool
uses. One is is you know, okay, now we
need to get around the CSP. We're the
attacker. We're stuck in the iframe. How
do we escape? Fun stuff. The other thing
that I was thinking is it's actually um
helpful for an attacker on a page where
that they can load in an iframe, but uh
you know it's cross origin and you you
need to be able to define the CSP for
that page. uh because you can do DOSs
specific scripts. Maybe there's a script
that um you know does something that
puts the the site in an insecure
position and then there's another script
that comes over and like makes it secure
again and you want to have that second
script not load. Well, you can load that
page inside of an iframe, set the CSP
for that page, and then block that
second script from loading if it's
being, you know, dynamically loaded up
um from a specific URL or something like
that. So very interesting uh very
interesting piece of functionality
whenever you can define security
controls for an origin that you don't
own right in this environment. Very very
interesting piece of functionality. So
um you know audience I challenge you
kind of let your brains uh spin a little
bit on how we could use a CSP uh in to
attack a victim page that we can embed
in an iframe because we can set the uh
content security policy for that. Very
interesting. Okay. Next attribute up is
the allow attribute. Okay. Now the allow
attribute is uh defines what's called
permission policy for that specific
page. And this gives access to resources
such as camera, mic, geoloc, etc. All of
those get sort of passed to the specific
um frame. Now uh I learned something
very very interesting recently. Uh I
wish I could shout out who told me, but
I can't. Uh so you know who you are if
you're listening. shout out to you. Um
that the iframes will even cross origin
iframes will inherit whatever
permissions the top level page has um as
far as permission policy goes. Uh this
is true especially if the allow um the
allow attribute this is necessary that
that the allow attribute you know say
all right pass through mic pass through
um you know camera etc that that that
iframe is allowed to access them and
then um it doesn't even matter that
there's a cross origin relationship
there the top page can sort of give
their permissions to uh the the lower
level page um and I think this creates a
really interesting scenario where you
have um sort of preview like functional
ity. Uh I I I think that that that the
top level origin that that may be doing
that previewing, you know, maybe
isolating your your code in a sandbox or
something like that may be endowed with
um particular permissions that you may
not want to give to the the bottom
iframe. Um and then sometimes get passed
through explicitly. Um uh so definitely
definitely keep an eye out for the allow
attribute on these on these iframes if
somebody is not aware of how they are
impacting um the the DOM's security when
when they're using it. Um the next uh
attribute that I had on the list was the
name attribute. And guys, this is one of
my favorite parts of like freaking
browser security. I don't know why I
love the name attribute so much. I just
think it's really helpful. Um the name
attribute allows you in an iframe
context allows you to set the name for a
window that is inside that iframe. And
the reason that's cool is because um
that name attribute is one of the only
things that doesn't change when you move
uh from origin to origin. Okay? So you
can have you know you can open up an
iframe, you can name it Bob and then you
navigate that iframe to a completely
different window and it's still um
called Bob. And I recently found uh in
in where did I read this? Somebody told
me this or I read it somewhere that this
was how they used to do this is from an
OG uh cross cross-domain communication
uh before the post message API came out
is they would set a message in the
window name and then they would redirect
to that other domain and the domain
would read the window and be like oh
okay here's the response message and
they read redirect back to the other
domain. Right? So that was how they
would do sort of cross-domain
communication. very interesting. Um uh
and the other cool thing about the name
attribute is it can be used to specify
what windows
uh specific uh window.open calls should
be opened into or um forms or a a links
can be pointed at, right? Um, and there
are a couple really cool niche
vulnerabilities that can happen where
um, you have a specific window open on
the page. The attacker controls the
ability to open um, a window into a
certain tab or frame uh, via the name
attribute and then you can sort of force
that that um, iframe or whatever to
contain the contents that you want as a
malicious actor. Um, very cool
vulnerability. I found it a couple
times. Feels amazing when you pull it
off. Um, we'll talk more about that
later. Uh, under the window.name name
hijacking vulnerability section. Um,
couple more uh attributes to cover and
then we'll kind of get to some of the
some of the meat on uh different attack
vectors you can use with an
iframe. Um, so the next one is refer
policy. This is a this is a pretty new
one. I I feel hasn't been around for too
long. Um, back in the good old days we
used to be able to just leak data via
the referer anytime. You know, if we
could inject an image tag into a page
and land like an OOTH code on that page
and the image would load, then we would
get that OOTH code on our server every
time because it was just yeeting the
whole refer out to whatever resource
loaded up on the page, which is totally
crazy now in retrospect, but it was
awesome back in the day. Um, and what
prevents us from doing that now is the
referral policy. Now, um I've said this
a couple times on the pod, but uh you
should definitely go back and listen to
the episode by JRock 17. um he drops an
amazing zeroday
misconfiguration/chrome and dump purify
fighting over stuff um on that episode
where essentially you can put a meta tag
affecting the referral policy of a
specific page uh into DOM purify and it
will get sanitized but somehow it still
has effect on the page um which is just
such a cool thing. So if you ever have a
DOM purify based injection uh and you're
trying to think h what can I do with
this you can change the referral policy
very very interesting thing very
impactful especially in in a scenario
where you know a lot of times when you
when you're going up against on purify
you have uh user controlled um HTML
right that's what they're that's what
they're purifying that's what they're
sanitizing um so you embed an an image
tag in there you set the refer policy to
unsafe URL you land it an unused used
oath code on that page via dirty
dancing, right? All of France Rosen and
then boom, you're you're good to go. Um,
so definitely very very interesting
piece there in there for policy. A
little bit less uh interesting referring
to iframes, but um I did have in my
notes here I forgot. There is a a really
interesting idea that I I kind of came
up with when I was thinking and prepping
for this episode about uh referral
policy and iframes and that was that I
finally found a um a use for the
clientside post messagebased open
redirect. Now I talked about this a
little bit on the gadgets episode that
we did a while back and we were like is
this really a gadget? And the answer is
no because if you have a frame reference
most of the time you have the ability to
redirect anyway. Um, but the the what's
interesting about this is that uh if you
want to embed a victim page inside of
your your um browser, you know, inside
of your attacker controlled page in an
iframe, right, and set the refer policy
that for that to unsafe URL and then uh
use a post message to navigate the page
inside of the iframe. Right? So the the
navigation comes from within the iframe
then you can leak the top level um URL
of that page via the referral um which
is a very valuable gadget much more
valuable of a gadget than a client side
uh post messagebased open redirect right
um so you know maybe you land an oath
code on there maybe you get a piece of
PII in the URI somehow um but that was
something that I hadn't really put
together in my brain before today that
that if if you can set the referral
policy. Once again, we're in this sort
of weird situation of like how are we
setting the referral policy for a cross
origin domain just cuz it's in our
iframe. It's a little bit it's a little
bit funky. Um but you don't really see
people set the referral policy. It's
mostly just screwing us because it's
implicitly um set to just the the top
level domain. Um so very very
interesting uh flow there. I'm
definitely going to keep my eye out for
that. I just thought of that like a
couple minutes before the episode. Um,
all right. Next up is the sandbox
attribute. This one is where we kind of
get into a little bit of meat. And I'm
not going to spend too much time here
because there's so many different
attributes that, you know, components
that can go into this attribute. But the
sandbox attribute for an iframe allows
you to isolate that iframe even more
from your current domain um, and control
it in very uh, clear ways. So some of
the most popular uh and useful
attributes for an attacker to be aware
of is uh allow scripts and allow same
origin. Those two uh are really
impactful. One allow scripts of course
allows you to run JavaScript within this
iframe. to allow same origin allows you
to have the same origin as the parent uh
frame uh and and access also the um
the uh like cookies and local storage
and some of those things that are tied
to that domain. Very very cool stuff. Um
allow forms, allow pop-ups, allow
pop-ups to escape sandbox and allow top
level navigations are also sort of like
second tier interesting to an attacker.
in my sort of rating system inside of
sandbox. Um allow forms obviously allows
you to do form based navigation. That's
a really cool way to get around um CSP
sometimes trigger some very impactful
stuff. Um allow popups, right? That
allows you to sort of swing pop open
another window. Something like that.
Allow pop-ups to escape sandbox um is
really cool. and and allow pop-ups
without to escape sandbox is also really
interesting because the pop-up window
that you spawn inherits the same sandbox
properties as the previous window,
right? So if you don't do allow same
origin and iframe is origin null, right?
Then uh and you do a popup on that, then
the website is also going to be origin
null. So it it like you can do some
really weird stuff with, you know,
window.open open inside of a allow
scripts iframe when it doesn't have same
origin. Very very fun, very fun stuff
there. So definitely investigate that if
you're into client side stuff. Um okay,
and the last one is allow top level
navigation. A lot of people don't know
this, but um you have a lot of power
when it comes to iframes and openers. Um
if if you are the opener uh of a
specific uh page, then you can redirect
that page at will anytime. If you are an
iframe within a page, you can also often
times redirect the the top level page.
Um, so there's a lot of power that comes
with that. Uh, and that can be really
helpful for an attacker if they're able
to inject an iframe somewhere into a
page or hijack an iframe. Um, there's a
lot of capabilities that that come
there. All right. And then the last one
that I had as far as attributes go is
the credential list attribute. Um, we
covered this recently on the pod like a
couple weeks ago, so I won't talk about
it too much, but essentially what it
allows you to do is sort of create a
siloed um, browsing context inside of
that iframe. And that means that you
know that iframe doesn't have access to
your cookies, none of your local
storage, none of that other stuff that
you would normally have access to in a
traditional iframe scenario. It's just
isolated. And so this is really helpful.
A buddy of mine recently had to do a an
XSS where you cannot uh send any same
site none cookookies and the same site
cookie non cookookie that he needed to
not be sent was set immediately whenever
you went to the page. So it was really
hard to exploit. Um and this credential
list uh was the
solution. Okay. All right. I'm going to
get some water and then we'll jump into
a couple attacks that I love with
iframes. All right. Let's see what we
got. All right. couple more uh a couple
of attacks that we we're going to talk
about with regards to iframes. Now, the
first one, uh is called window.name
hijacking. Okay, and this one is a
little bit tricky to
understand. Um uh but I'm going to do my
best over the audio medium. Okay,
consider this. You have an attacker
controlled page and you window.open a
victim page. The victim then clicks a
button on that page which triggers
another window.open pin with a very
specific name that you know the value
of. What an attacker can then do is
create an iframe on their own page uh
before the button is clicked just to be
clear that has that same name. Now the
the um victim page and the attacker page
are in a link linked browsing context
because of the opener relationship right
between those those those two pages. Um,
and because they share the same browsing
context, they will also be able to
reference each other's frames. Um, and
what will happen then is if an attacker
knows the origin that the victim will be
opening the tab into, so if they're
going to do a window.open on like site
site.com or whatever, then uh they can
embed their own attacker iframe inside
of the attacker controlled page that
points to uh site.com that is on
site.com, right? Maybe you find a 404
page or something that doesn't have
X-frame options on it and you embed it
in in your page and you name that I
frame the same thing as the victim will
be opening with window.open. Okay. And
what's going to happen in that scenario
is when the user clicks the button and
it opens the popup, it is not going to
pop up at all. It is going to open that
attacker or that victim's uh new pop-up
window into your iframe that's on your
attacker controlled page. Now the reason
why that is uh interesting is that
there's often a lot of implicit
relationship stuff that occurs um
between uh opened windows uh and their
their opener. So that the opener will
take that frame reference and be like
all right I'm just going to use this
frame reference as like the source of
truth as whether I should trust this
post message or not or or or when you
know I'm going to keep checking the
origin of that that window reference and
when it comes back to my origin then I'm
going to trust the data that comes out
of it. you know, I'm gonna grab from
like the hash or something like that.
I've seen that a couple times. So, what
you can do by hijacking that frame,
obviously, you're the parent of that
frame. It's in your own page. So, you
control, you know, where that where that
frame is pointed to. So, you simply
redirect that frame to an attacker
controlled page uh and send the post
message back to its its uh opener uh
saying, "Hey, yo, I'm the frame you
opened. Here's the data." You know, and
and pass it through um and exploit it
that way. or if it's looking to, you
know, get a call back or something like
that on that frame, then, you know, you
get whatever data you want to call back,
throw it in the hash, and then redirect
it back to whatever call back page the
the opener was expecting, and it will
parse it just like, you know, it just
coming back from the call that it that
it did. Um, so this is this is a very
cool attack. I've exploited this several
times. I think probably less than 10
times, but still very very fun attack.
You know, when it works, um, it's a
blast. And I just love that we can
control where a pop-up goes, right?
Like, isn't that such a cool thing that
a victim is expecting sort of a pop-up
to happen and instead it just opens into
an attacker controlled iframe and now
you're focused on the attacker's page
and your your frame now is populated
with that victim's data that they were
trying to open up. Very cool. Um, all
right. The next one is uh openfaced
iframe sandwich. Okay, this is the next
attack that was on my list. Now, I've
talked about this a couple times on the
pod, and I I wanted to bring it up again
because a guy named Cooper Young um who
I helped with an openf face iframe
sandwich uh recently did a write up, I
want to say like two or three days ago
on the uh iframe sandwich. Okay. And the
writeup was great. It explains how
everything happens. Um we were able to
pop a bug with this, which was really
fun. Um, and yeah, uh, I wanted to go
ahead and review it for the for the
listeners of the pod because it is a
little challenging, I have to say. Okay,
now I'm gonna do my best to describe
this um, with my two hands, but maybe I
don't know, maybe I'll put a graphic up
on the screen. We'll see. Um, uh, this,
uh, this episode goes to production
pretty quickly, so I'm not sure we're
going to have time to this, but I I'll
try to explain it anyway. Um, okay. So,
we've got an attacker frame, right? and
a victim frame. And uh what happens in
this scenario is that uh the the
attacker gets an
XSS on an origin that is I framed in a
victim tab. Okay. So consider the
scenario where you've got um oh one of
the real examples from my my experiences
was I was able to pop an XSS on the
origin that controls um uh the user's
mail settings, right? like, you know, do
you want to subscribe to our newsletter
or whatever, right? It's like sometimes
those things are super easy to pop and
they're embedded in an iframe on like
www, right? Um, so you're like, okay,
what can I do with this? It isn't really
in scope. I want to affect www. What do
I do? Well, here's what you do. So, you
from the from the attacker's page, you
open a frame. That's the victim page.
The victim page has that um you I'm
going to call it the mail domain uh I
framed into it. Now, as the attacker,
you I frame on your page uh your XSS
into the mail to the mail domain, right?
So, now both pages have an iframe to the
mail domain and they're open and they
have an opener relationship with one
another, right? Uh I guess one of them
has an opener relationship, one of them
has an open relationship. So what you
then do is from the attacker's frame
inside of the iframe, you go up to the
attacker's top level page over to the
victim tab and down into the victim's
frame. Now these two, you know, iframed
pages have the same origin, which means
they can access each other's DOM. So the
attacker with the malicious XSS then
affects the DOM within that page or
grabs whatever information is is out of
it on that page. In my scenario, there
was a bunch of PII leaked into that from
the parent when it tells uh the um mail
domain, hey, this is the user I want you
to control the mail for. Um and you you
get impact that way. Let me grab some
water. Okay. And now I'm back. I I just
had like a cough attack from that little
uh tickle in my throat. But that's the
open iframe sandwich, openfaced iframe
sandwich. Um really cool exploit. Love
to use it. Um okay. And then last but
not least is clickjacking. Of course,
you can't really not mention clickjing
when you talk about iframe security in
in in web security. Like I said before,
iframe gets a bad rap all the time. And
[Music]
clickjacking gets a bad rap all the time
and I don't really know why. It's it it
can be very impactful when done
correctly. Um, and I just wanted to say,
you know, I built a a clickjacking PC
recently and um, and it was uh,
impactful, as I said, and um, the most
overpowered way of doing this, by the
way, is just writing some very quick and
easy code to just have the iframe follow
your cursor. Right? Whenever your cursor
is not centered on the invisible iframe,
then just move it so that it is. Um, and
that's really easy to code. I'm pretty
sure I told cursor to do it and it just
like one shot got it right and it was
totally fine. You center the iframe, you
know, where the user's cursor is uh over
whatever button you want to click and it
doesn't even matter. The user can be
like running their their cursor around
and it will still always click the right
button. Um, which is super overpowered
in my opinion. Um, so very cool stuff
there. Had to mention clickjing. Don't
submit crappy clickjing reports. Build
out the full PC. Um, and you will you
will very likely get paid for those if
they're not explicitly out of scope
because the impact is there or it should
be there if you're reporting it. Okay,
last but not least, um, couple fun facts
about iframes that have just landed me a
couple bugs recently. Um, this is a fun
one uh from the critical research lab
actually. Um, the content security
policies frame ancestor attribute will
override xframe options header. Okay, so
let me say that again. The x-frame
options header. Of course, you guys know
what the x-ray options header is. It uh
it has, you know, it controls whether a
page can be ifframed or not. So, what
you'll often see is xremera options
deny, right? Which so this page cannot
be framed at all. GG, game over. Well,
if there's a content security policy
that has a frame ancestor um attribute
in it and that defines you know some
pages that the page can be uh uh iframed
from then that will override xframe
options and be given priority which is
very interesting because a lot of times
what happens in in browser security is
if there's a conflict between two you
know security related entities the the
one that they go for is the one that is
more safe the one that is least
permissive. Right. But in this scenario,
we actually have it going with the one
that is that is um I'm sorry. Yeah, the
one that's least permissive. In this
scenario, we have one going for the one
that is more permissive. Kind of odd.
Okay. Um let me see what else was on
here. I know I had a couple more. I've
already mentioned that iframes can
redirect their parents and openers by
default. That's pretty cool. Oh, the
last one here is is that I have to
mention is um window.frames
frames is also is one of the very few uh
attributes that can be accessed by a
cross origin um sort of relationship
that window reference here. Right? So
let's say I've got attacker.com and I've
got victim.com and they have like a
relationship where they have a window
frame. Um the attacker can see how many
I frames the victim has uh in that page.
Now this is really helpful for a lot of
reasons. um from a cross-sight leak
perspective, but one of the ones that
I've always thought was really cool was
like, wouldn't it be amazing if there
was a a page where you could like very
easily update the hash and it would, you
know, give you an iframe for every like
result of a search or something like
that. So, you just put in, you know, the
hash A and it like says, okay, there's
like six six of them. And you say B and
then there's like four of them. And you
say C and then there's just one of them.
And you say E and then it says, nope.
and then you say D and it says yes
there's one you know so you can do like
you can really sort of character by
character brute force
um codes in sort of like a cross leak
scenario if the number of iframes
changes uh based off of what is uh
controlled by the attacker very very
cool stuff I've used this several times
to land vulnerabilities
um and it's something I always check
because I'm like wouldn't it be sick if
I could just leak this data via via
cross uh like a cross origin property on
a window reference.
Um, yeah, every time I every time I
think about that, my brain just keeps
turning and turning and turning like
where can I use that? Where where are
there iframes that are relevant to data
that an attacker can
control? All right, y'all. That's about
a wrap. Uh, I I think that is a good,
you know, basic overview of the iframes.
I'm I'm not sure that there's anything
that's really essential that uh I missed
there. Um, so I hope you enjoyed it. Let
me know what you guys think about these
sort of like oneoff uh single single
person talking um sort of technical deep
dives on a topic you're comfortable
with. So let me know what you guys
think. That's the pod for this week.
Peace. And that's a wrap on this episode
of Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild. If you're a
full-time hunter, it's a great time,
trust me. All right, I'll see you there.